import React, { useState } from 'react'

export default function QuizUsiungArray() {
    let  [radiostate , setRadioState] = useState({})
    let [score, setScore] = useState(0)
    let [rightanswer, setRightAnswer] = useState(0)
    let [wrong, setWrong] = useState(0)
    let [flag, setflag] = useState(false)

    let Quiz_array = [
        {
            qno : 1,
            question : "Who's the founder of Pakistan?",
            options : ["Quaid -e Azam" , "Allama Iqbal" , "Modi"],
            correct : "Quaid -e Azam"
        },
        {
            qno: 2,
            question: "What is the capital of Pakistan?",
            options: ["Karachi", "Islamabad", "Lahore"],
            correct: "Islamabad"
        },
        {
            qno: 3,
            question: "In which year did Pakistan gain independence?",
            options: ["1947", "1950", "1965"],
            correct: "1947"
        },
        {
            qno: 4,
            question: "Who was the first Prime Minister of Pakistan?",
            options: ["Liaquat Ali Khan", "Benazir Bhutto", "Nawaz Sharif"],
            correct: "Liaquat Ali Khan"
        },
        {
            qno: 5,
            question: "Which city is known as the 'City of Lights' in Pakistan?",
            options: ["Karachi", "Lahore", "Islamabad"],
            correct: "Karachi"
        },
        {
            qno: 6,
            question: "What is the national language of Pakistan?",
            options: ["Urdu", "Punjabi", "English"],
            correct: "Urdu"
        },
        {
            qno: 7,
            question: "Who was the first President of Pakistan?",
            options: ["Iskander Mirza", "Zulfiqar Ali Bhutto", "Pervez Musharraf"],
            correct: "Iskander Mirza"
        },
        {
            qno: 8,
            question: "What is the national animal of Pakistan?",
            options: ["Markhor", "Lion", "Elephant"],
            correct: "Markhor"
        },
        {
            qno: 9,
            question: "Which mountain is the highest in Pakistan?",
            options: ["K2", "Nanga Parbat", "Mount Everest"],
            correct: "K2"
        },
        {
            qno: 10,
            question: "Who was the founder of the All India Muslim League?",
            options: ["Allama Iqbal", "Muhammad Ali Jinnah", "Syed Ahmad Khan"],
            correct: "Syed Ahmad Khan"
        },
        {
            qno: 11,
            question: "In which year was Pakistan's constitution adopted?",
            options: ["1956", "1962", "1973"],
            correct: "1973"
        }

    ]

    function get_Radio_Button_Value(q, r){
        setRadioState((a)=>({
            ...a, // spread operator
            [q] : r
        }))
    }
    function QuizLogic(){
        console.log(radiostate);
        Quiz_array.map((abc)=>{
            if (radiostate[abc.qno] === abc.correct) {
                setScore(score+=5);
                setRightAnswer(rightanswer++);

            }
            else{
                setWrong(wrong++);
            }
        })
        console.log(score)
        console.log(rightanswer)
        console.log(wrong)
        setflag(true)
 
    }
  return (
    <div>
            <h1>Quiz Using Array</h1>
            <hr />
            {Quiz_array.map((a)=>(
                <div>
                    <h4>{a.qno}. {a.question}</h4>
                    {a.options.map((opt,i)=>(
                       <div>
                        <input 
                        type="radio"
                        value={opt}
                        name={`q${a.qno}`}
                        onChange={() => get_Radio_Button_Value(a.qno,opt)}/> {opt}
                        </div>
                    ) )}
                </div>
            )) }

            <button className='btn btn-primary' onClick={QuizLogic}>Submit</button>
            {flag && (
                <div>
                    <h4>Score is {score}</h4>
                    <h4>Right answer is {rightanswer}</h4>
                    <h4>Wrong is {wrong}</h4>

                </div>
            )}
    </div>
  )
}
